Everybody loved him... Everybody disappeared. The journey is everything.
Jerry Maguire is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Cameron Crowe.
Jerry Maguire used to be a typical sports agent: willing to do just about anything he could to get
the biggest possible contracts for his clients, plus a nice commission for himself.
Then, one day, he suddenly has second thoughts about what he's really doing.
When he voices these doubts, he ends up losing his job and all of his
clients, save Rod Tidwell, an egomaniacal football player.
Jerry Maguire, played by Tom Cruise.
Dorothy Boyd, played by Renée Zellweger.
Rod Tidwell, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Avery Bishop, played by Kelly Preston.
Frank Cushman, played by Jerry O'Connell.
Bob Sugar, played by Jay Mohr.
Jerry Maguire is a 1996 American sports romantic comedy
film written and directed by Cameron Crowe.
It was produced by Crowe and James L.
Brooks, respectively for Vinyl Films and Gracie Films and distributed by
Sony Pictures Releasing under the TriStar Pictures label.
It stars Tom Cruise as the titular sports agent character, alongside Cuba Gooding Jr., Renée
Zellweger, Kelly Preston, Jerry O'Connell, Jay Mohr, Bonnie Hunt and Regina King.
It was released in North American theaters on December 13, 1996.
Jerry Maguire was inspired by an experience with the sports agent Leigh Steinberg, a technical consultant for the film and his client,
Tim McDonald (who makes a cameo appearance in this film) during the 1993 NFL season when free agency was introduced.
The film was also partly inspired by a 28-page memo written
at Disney in 1991 by Jeffrey Katzenberg.
Jerry Maguire received positive reviews for its performances and screenplay.
It grossed more than $273 million worldwide against its $50 million budget.
It was the ninth-highest-grossing film of 1996.
It was nominated for five Academy Awards, including Best Picture
and Best Actor for Cruise, with Cuba Gooding Jr.
winning Best Supporting Actor, in addition to the Screen
Actors Guild Award in the same category.
Cruise won the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a
Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
Jerry Maguire gained a cult following and has spawned several catchphrases into popular
culture, such as "you had me at 'hello'", "you complete me" and "show me the money".
The film explores themes of career, sports, stadium,
american football, single mother.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.